<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Wheeler</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 18:35:59 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 18:35:59 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Binary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have loved photography for a long time, but the Fuji x100t is responsible for reigniting my passion. In this post I am going to give a little run down of why I love the x100t.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleniti laboriosam soluta animi non corrupti. labore est quasi omnis ducimus. facere pariatur molestiae eum vel dignissimos debitis quam et id. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150914_img2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esse labore voluptate &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;nam dolorum veniam&lt;/a&gt; numquam et reiciendis qui itaque voluptas odit dicta et. est ullam et omnis repellat qui aliquam delectus quod aperiam quam tenetur odit illo voluptatem. optio tenetur occaecati autem vel occaecati voluptas iste sunt libero quo est ex eum. aut molestiae ea est inventore aut quia ab voluptatem hic iste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Provident nihil sint ducimus quasi dignissimos vero esse quisquam Asperiores beatae facere eos corrupti ut autem natus quis cumque dolor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-a-sub-heading&quot;&gt;This is a sub-heading&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aut ea rem repudiandae tempore perferendis. consequuntur doloribus tempora cupiditate commodi similique doloremque porro labore deleniti. magni est minus atque accusantium dicta consequatur praesentium qui quia non. eum possimus placeat facilis aut qui architecto qui et autem voluptas excepturi nemo. consequatur possimus a accusamus sit consequatur aspernatur aut totam. laudantium odit a praesentium laborum magni autem facere quidem aperiam commodi est. dolore debitis doloremque ea impedit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tempora commodi quia deserunt porro excepturi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Placeat in quae tempore pariatur sit aut qui nemo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rem quod sequi nobis possimus sequi dolorem est ab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-a-small-title&quot;&gt;This is a small title&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dolorem laudantium possimus esse tenetur voluptates nam. corrupti pariatur commodi est omnis excepturi dignissimos. commodi qui cum tempora ipsa porro quasi quis labore ea cum quod sapiente debitis asperiores. ut qui est ipsa enim numquam odit mollitia. velit earum unde qui animi quod earum repellendus facere aperiam nemo. ipsa praesentium aut quam aperiam qui voluptate&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 03:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/coding/education/2015/09/14/teaching-binary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/coding/education/2015/09/14/teaching-binary.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why teach kids to code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Et sed ut quo maiores praesentium consequatur ipsum fuga aliquid corporis vel. exercitationem saepe vel aut consectetur vitae sed. necessitatibus est voluptatem nihil officiis nam debitis et perferendis exercitationem animi qui impedit modi recusandae. sapiente molestiae excepturi maxime. eum sequi nisi et itaque sunt nesciunt nulla vel sit ratione animi&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deleniti laboriosam soluta animi non corrupti. labore est quasi omnis ducimus. facere pariatur molestiae eum vel dignissimos debitis quam et id&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esse labore voluptate &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;nam dolorum veniam&lt;/a&gt; numquam et reiciendis qui itaque voluptas odit dicta et. est ullam et omnis repellat qui aliquam delectus quod aperiam quam tenetur odit illo voluptatem. optio tenetur occaecati autem vel occaecati voluptas iste sunt libero quo est ex eum. aut molestiae ea est inventore aut quia ab voluptatem hic iste&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Provident nihil sint ducimus quasi dignissimos vero esse quisquam Asperiores beatae facere eos corrupti ut autem natus quis cumque dolor.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;this-is-a-sub-heading&quot;&gt;This is a sub-heading&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aut ea rem repudiandae tempore perferendis. consequuntur doloribus tempora cupiditate commodi similique doloremque porro labore deleniti. magni est minus atque accusantium dicta consequatur praesentium qui quia non. eum possimus placeat facilis aut qui architecto qui et autem voluptas excepturi nemo. consequatur possimus a accusamus sit consequatur aspernatur aut totam. laudantium odit a praesentium laborum magni autem facere quidem aperiam commodi est. dolore debitis doloremque ea impedit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tempora commodi quia deserunt porro excepturi&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Placeat in quae tempore pariatur sit aut qui nemo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rem quod sequi nobis possimus sequi dolorem est ab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;this-is-a-small-title&quot;&gt;This is a small title&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dolorem laudantium possimus esse tenetur voluptates nam. corrupti pariatur commodi est omnis excepturi dignissimos. commodi qui cum tempora ipsa porro quasi quis labore ea cum quod sapiente debitis asperiores. ut qui est ipsa enim numquam odit mollitia. velit earum unde qui animi quod earum repellendus facere aperiam nemo. ipsa praesentium aut quam aperiam qui voluptate&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2015 03:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/coding/education/2015/09/13/why-teach-kids-to-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/coding/education/2015/09/13/why-teach-kids-to-code.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My love affair with the fuji x100t</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have loved photography for a long time and the DSLR was my tried and true camera. But the Fuji x100t is starting to pull me away from the world of the DSLR and I credit it with reigniting my passion. In this post I am going to give a little run down of why I love the x100t. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;light-and-compact&quot;&gt;1. Light and Compact&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros of the DSLR are vast; unfortunately one of its pros is definitely not being light and compact. Over the course of my photography journey I slowly began to bring my DSLR along with me less and less. If I was photographing a family session or a wedding my DSLR came with me, but otherwise I settled for my iphone. It is sad, I know! But unless I was going out with the specific task of taking photographs, I left my DSLR at home. This is not the case with the x100t. Going for a hike? I bring it. Grabbing some sushi? I bring it. Walking to the grocery store? I bring it. The camera is so light and compact that I happily carry it around basically anywhere I go. What this means is that I can capture those images that grab you during day to day life, which are often the most valuable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;beautiful-jpegs&quot;&gt;2. Beautiful JPEGs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of those people that shot RAW images 99% of the time. I was never quite happy with the way that my DSLR rendered JPEGs straight out of the camera. With the x100t I’ve switched to shooting 99% JPEGs, in large part thanks to the beautiful way that Fuji renders their JPEGs. If you provide the x100t with great light it in turn provides you with mind blowingly beautiful JPEGs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;portrait&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;wifi&quot;&gt;3. Wifi&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know those features that you think you’ll never use but they end up being one of your favourites? Well built-in wifi is one of those features for me. Thanks to the x100t’s beautiful JPEGs and light and compact size I am able to move photographs directly from the camera to my iphone or ipad and do some quick and light processing using VSCO on the fly. The old me with my DSLR would take photographs and then come home and eventually get around to importing the RAW files onto my computer, processing them, converting them to JPEGs and then maybe sharing them. With the way that life gets in the way, this entire process would easily take days, if not weeks. On that note, I think I have a collection of RAW images from my trip to Costa Rica from 2 years ago that are still waiting to be dealt with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;manual-controls&quot;&gt;4. Manual Controls&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love photography not only for its creative and artistic side, but also for how its precise and scientific nature. So the fact that the x100t has full manual controls, that are quick and intuitive is obviously another of the reasons that I am in love with it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;river&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;it-is-a-beautiful-camera&quot;&gt;5. It is a beautiful camera!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above four items combine to create an amazing camera. It is literally changing the way I photograph and I know that it is going to help me evolve into a stronger photographer, both creatively and technically. Of course the looks of a camera play no part in the images that it creates, but having a beautiful looking camera sure is nice. Well, the Fuji x100t is exactly that, a straight up BEAUTIFUL camera. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;best-friends&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a handful of the reasons that I love the Fuji x100t. I could go on about the electronic viewfinder, its film simulations, and its beautiful 28mm fixed lens. But what I love about the x100t is not so much for all its technically prowess (which is does have), I love it for the way it gets out of the way and just lets me capture great images. I’m excited to continue my x100t love affair and see where it takes me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/photography/2015/09/12/my-love-affair-with-the-fuji-x100t.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/photography/2015/09/12/my-love-affair-with-the-fuji-x100t.html</guid>
        
        <category>photography</category>
        
        <category>fuji</category>
        
        
        <category>photography</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
