<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Andrew Wheeler</title>
    <description>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.
</description>
    <link>/</link>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 13:07:39 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2015 13:07:39 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why teach kids to code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2015 03:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/coding/education/2015/10/05/why-teach-kids-to-code.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/coding/education/2015/10/05/why-teach-kids-to-code.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Teaching Binary</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It is my feeling that many students are lacking in their fundamental number sense. To improve this it is important to show students the inner workings of the concepts they are learning. Ask a student to count to the number of students in their class and they will likely do so happily and confidently. Now tell them that they did a great job counting using the base 10 (or decimal) system, but how about they try counting using base 2 (or binary) system. They would likely give you a strange and puzzled look, and rightfully so. Why bother teaching them another system, as it’s not like they are going to use binary in their day to day life? Well, I believe that it is incredibly valuable to realize that the number system that we use in our day to day life is just one of many. Too much of math is thought to be some sort of magical system that we just take for granted. Also, understanding other systems will improve and help to add context to the base 10 system, thereby improving their day to day number sense.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;base-10-system-decimal&quot;&gt;Base 10 System (Decimal)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on the age of your students you might get some ‘I know this’ stares when you start talking about the decimal system. But again, I think we are so used to this system that we take some things for granted. I like to ask the students questions like “Why do you think we call it the decimal system?” and “Why is it also referred to base 10, specifically why 10?”. If they give you some blank stares I generally follow up with “What is a decade? How about a decathalon?” and this usually leads to a “Hey it is something to do with 10!”. Great, but why 10? Well how many digits do we have in our counting system? Again, this might seem obvious but many students will count from 1-9 and then continue on to 10, 11, 12 and on. This is where I focus on the term ‘digit’. And within a few minutes, we have identified that it is base 10 because there are 10 digits. We then continue on from here, possibly using a table similar to the one shown below, and start to apply the decimal system.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150914_img3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;baseten&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;base-2-system-binary&quot;&gt;Base 2 System (Binary)&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the foundation set by the review of the decimal system should pay off. Questions such as, “Why do they call it the binary system?” and “Why base 2?” should give some relatively quick answers. A bicycle has two wheels and we are called bipeds because we have two legs, so good chance that the number 2 has something to do with why it is called binary. So the magic number was 10 for the decimal system and it was because there was 10 digits, therefore it would make sense if the binary system had two digits. Except, we don’t call them digits, that is only for the decimal system. With the binary system we call them bits, so the binary system has 2 bits in the exact same way as the decimal system has 10 digits. Now as you continue to build up and connect the students understanding of the decimal system to the new (but similar) binary system, you should be able to construct a table similar to the one below. With this table, students should be able to relatively easily convert decimal values into binary ones. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150914_img2.png&quot; alt=&quot;basetwo&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;so-computers-use-binary-prove-it&quot;&gt;So computer’s use binary? Prove it!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, so the kids know about binary now…big deal. And at this point I would agree because it is with context that things become interesting. Talking about how computers only understand binary, so all your of programs that you write are converted into binary using a compiler is pretty cool. But again, it adds very little context and they are just left with accepting it is a fact that is being told to them. So what does a teacher do when presented with the difficult teaching situation? &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.smh.com.au/entertainment/music/psys-gangnam-style-breaks-the-internet-20141204-11zusj.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Resort to music videos on YouTube!&lt;/a&gt; Everyone knows Gangnam Style and some of your students might also be aware of the fact that it was responsible for breaking YouTube. But now they actually have the knowledge and understanding to grasp exactly how that happened. It is also a great piece of evidence to show that computer use binary, because if YouTube uses it then it must be true.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2015 03:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/coding/education/2015/09/22/teaching-binary.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/coding/education/2015/09/22/teaching-binary.html</guid>
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
        
        <category>coding</category>
        
        <category>education</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My love affair with the fuji x100t</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have loved photography for a long time and the DSLR was my tried and true camera. But the Fuji x100t is starting to pull me away from the world of the DSLR and I credit it with reigniting my passion. In this post I am going to give a little run down of why I love the x100t. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;light-and-compact&quot;&gt;1. Light and Compact&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The pros of the DSLR are vast; unfortunately one of its pros is definitely not being light and compact. Over the course of my photography journey I slowly began to bring my DSLR along with me less and less. If I was photographing a family session or a wedding my DSLR came with me, but otherwise I settled for my iphone. It is sad, I know! But unless I was going out with the specific task of taking photographs, I left my DSLR at home. This is not the case with the x100t. Going for a hike? I bring it. Grabbing some sushi? I bring it. Walking to the grocery store? I bring it. The camera is so light and compact that I happily carry it around basically anywhere I go. What this means is that I can capture those images that grab you during day to day life, which are often the most valuable.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;dog&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;beautiful-jpegs&quot;&gt;2. Beautiful JPEGs&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was one of those people that shot RAW images 99% of the time. I was never quite happy with the way that my DSLR rendered JPEGs straight out of the camera. With the x100t I’ve switched to shooting 99% JPEGs, in large part thanks to the beautiful way that Fuji renders their JPEGs. If you provide the x100t with great light it in turn provides you with mind blowingly beautiful JPEGs.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;portrait&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;wifi&quot;&gt;3. Wifi&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know those features that you think you’ll never use but they end up being one of your favourites? Well built-in wifi is one of those features for me. Thanks to the x100t’s beautiful JPEGs and light and compact size I am able to move photographs directly from the camera to my iphone or ipad and do some quick and light processing using VSCO on the fly. The old me with my DSLR would take photographs and then come home and eventually get around to importing the RAW files onto my computer, processing them, converting them to JPEGs and then maybe sharing them. With the way that life gets in the way, this entire process would easily take days, if not weeks. On that note, I think I have a collection of RAW images from my trip to Costa Rica from 2 years ago that are still waiting to be dealt with.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;beach&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;manual-controls&quot;&gt;4. Manual Controls&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love photography not only for its creative and artistic side, but also for how its precise and scientific nature. So the fact that the x100t has full manual controls, that are quick and intuitive is obviously another of the reasons that I am in love with it. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;river&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;it-is-a-beautiful-camera&quot;&gt;5. It is a beautiful camera!&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above four items combine to create an amazing camera. It is literally changing the way I photograph and I know that it is going to help me evolve into a stronger photographer, both creatively and technically. Of course the looks of a camera play no part in the images that it creates, but having a beautiful looking camera sure is nice. Well, the Fuji x100t is exactly that, a straight up BEAUTIFUL camera. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/20150912_img7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;best-friends&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are just a handful of the reasons that I love the Fuji x100t. I could go on about the electronic viewfinder, its film simulations, and its beautiful 28mm fixed lens. But what I love about the x100t is not so much for all its technically prowess (which is does have), I love it for the way it gets out of the way and just lets me capture great images. I’m excited to continue my x100t love affair and see where it takes me!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:20:05 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>/photography/2015/09/12/my-love-affair-with-the-fuji-x100t.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/photography/2015/09/12/my-love-affair-with-the-fuji-x100t.html</guid>
        
        <category>photography</category>
        
        <category>fuji</category>
        
        
        <category>photography</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
